Are you ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
KIDS:
Aye, aye, Captain!
儿童：
是啊是啊，队长！
I can't hear you.
我听不到你说话。
[ louder]:
Aye, aye, Captain!
[更大声]：
是啊是啊，队长！
♪ Oh...
♪ 哦...
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants!♪
♪ 海绵宝宝！♪
♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he. ♪
♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的。 ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants!♪
♪ 海绵宝宝！♪
♪ If nautical nonsense be
something you wish... ♪
♪ 如果航海方面的废话是
你想要的东西...♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants!♪
♪ 海绵宝宝！♪
♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish. ♪
♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通。 ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants!♪
♪ 海绵宝宝！♪
♪ Ready?
SpongeBob SquarePants! ♪
♪ 准备好了吗？
海绵宝宝！ ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants!
♪ 海绵宝宝！
[ laughs heartily]
[开怀大笑]
[ plays airy tune]
[演奏轻快的曲子]
Captioning sponsored
by MTV NETWORKS
字幕赞助
由 MTV 网络提供
[ SpongeBob and Patrick
laughing]
[海绵宝宝和帕特里克
笑]
Whoa!
哇！
[ both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
[ laughing heartily]
[开怀大笑]
You're it.
你就是它。
[ both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
You're it.
你就是它。
Wait, Pat--
you're it!
等等，帕特——
你就是它！
[ screams]
[尖叫声]
The sign!
标志！
[ laughter turns to fear]
[笑声转为恐惧]
[ yells]
[大喊]
[ thud]
[砰]
Patrick!
帕特里克！
Let me help you
out of there, buddy.
让我来帮助你
离开那里，伙计。
Is the rest of you down there?
你们其他人都在下面吗？
The rest of me is up here.
我的其余部分都在这里。
Ooh, you had me
worried there, buddy.
哦，你有我
那里很担心，伙计。
[ laughs]
[笑]
Here's your head.
这是你的头。
[ laughs obnoxiously]
[讨厌地笑]
I find all this laughter
to be highly illogical.
我发现这一切的笑声
非常不合逻辑。
Well, let's stop laughing
and let's start fishing.
好吧，我们别笑了
让我们开始钓鱼吧。
Go ahead,
you get first crack.
继续吧，
你得到了第一个破解。
Look at them-- these graceful
stoic creatures of the deep.
看看他们——这些优雅的
坚忍的深海生物。
Huh? Those are
some big words, Pat.
啊？那些是
一些大话，帕特。
I've never heard you
use them before.
我从来没有听说过你
之前使用它们。
Nonsense, my vocabulary
is infinitely expanding.
废话，我的词汇
正在无限扩大。
Well, let's expand
our jellyfish nets.
嗯，我们来扩展一下
我们的水母网。
Come on, Patrick.
来吧，帕特里克。
Look, buddy,
I captured one.
看，伙计，
我抓获了一只。
Yes, I captured one
as well
是的，我抓到了一张
还有
without disturbing
its delicate ecosystem.
不打扰
其脆弱的生态系统。
It is wrong
to harness nature
这是错误的
驾驭自然
in such
a barbaric manner.
在这样的
一种野蛮的方式。
Okay.
好的。
What do you
want to do?
你想让我做什么？
Let us go off and admire
让我们出发去欣赏吧
the beauty and
fragility of nature.
美丽和
自然的脆弱性。
Pretty.
漂亮的。
Yes, quite.
是的，相当。
Fragile.
脆弱的。
Indeed.
的确。
Come on, Patrick,
let's do something fun.
来吧，帕特里克，
我们来做点有趣的事吧。
Oh, you want to run
some statistics
哦，你想跑
一些统计数据
or observe phenomenon
或观察现象
and render hypothesis
of said phenomenon?
并提出假设
上述现象？
I was thinking
more like jumping rope
我在想
更像是跳绳
or one-legged races,
or playing duck-duck-
hermit crab.
或单腿赛跑，
或者玩鸭鸭游戏
寄居蟹。
Doesn't feel like fun.
感觉不太好玩。
How about some jokes.
讲点笑话怎么样。
[ sighs]
[叹气]
What's the difference
between a guitar
and a jellyfish?
有什么区别
吉他之间
还有水母？
You can't strum a jellyfish.
你无法拨动水母。
Yes!
是的！
[ laughs obnoxiously]
[讨厌地笑]
[ strums beautiful chord]
[弹奏优美的和弦]
Oh, my,
look at the time.
哦，我的，
看看时间。
I really must be going.
我真的必须走了。
What's wrong with Patrick?
帕特里克怎么了？
I sure hope he gets better soon.
我当然希望他尽快好起来。
Are you better, Pat?
你好点了吗，帕特？
Uh, what are you doing?
呃，你在做什么？
Just studying
this amazing subspecies.
刚刚学习
这个惊人的亚种。
I'll show you subspecies.
我将向您展示亚种。
Want to visit
Squidward?
想要参观
章鱼哥？
Since I am finished
with my work,
既然我已经完成了
和我的工作，
I'll humor you
in your trivial pursuits.
我会逗你开心
在你琐碎的追求中。
[ playing off-key melody]
[演奏走调旋律]
I'd recognize that
piece anywhere:
我会认识到这一点
任何地方的一块：
Cornelius Pufferfish's Opus 67,
"Symphony in Blue."
科尼利厄斯河豚的作品 67，
“蓝色交响曲”。
Patrick?
帕特里克？
It's a beautiful piece.
这是一件美丽的作品。
Execution needs
some work.
执行需求
一些工作。
May I suggest that
on the seventh bar
我可以建议一下吗
在第七小节
of the adagio andante
that you add a little fortissimo
慢板行板
你添加一点强音
on the arpeggiated b-flat scale?
在降b调琶音音阶上？
Wow, I never thought
to do it like that.
哇，我从来没想过
那样做。
Well, that is
because you rarely think.
嗯，那就是
因为你很少思考。
How do you know
all that?
你怎么知道
所有这些？
A creative outlet provides
a spiritual release
创意渠道提供
一种精神上的释放
and helps facilitate
a healthy mental balance.
并有助于促进
健康的心理平衡。
[ inhales deeply]
[深吸一口气]
Does that include [ belching]
belch talking?
这包括[打嗝]吗
打嗝说话？
Mr. SquarePants,
I find your humor vulgar.
方裤先生，
我觉得你的幽默很粗俗。
I had no idea you
were so knowledgeable,
Patrick.
我不知道你
知识渊博，
帕特里克.
Do you think
you could be
my musical mentor?
你认为
你可能是
我的音乐导师？
Uh, guys?
呃，伙计们？
Let's take it
from the top.
让我们接受吧
从顶部。
[ squeaky notes]
[吱吱作响的音符]
Not so excellent,
Squidward.
没有那么优秀，
章鱼哥。
Let me demonstrate
the proper technique.
让我演示一下
正确的技术。
On second thought,
practice makes perfect.
再一想，
熟能生巧。
Let's begin.
让我们开始吧。
[ playing nose]
[玩鼻子]
Uh, thank you, my good chap.
嗯，谢谢你，我的好朋友。
Unfortunately this is
a solo piece for clarinet only.
不幸的是这是
一首单簧管独奏曲。
And one, two, three, four.
还有一、二、三、四。
[ Squidward playing off-key]
[章鱼哥走调]
PATRICK:
Stop! Enough!
帕特里克：
停下来！足够的！
Find yourself a new mentor!
为自己寻找一位新导师！
Now that you're free,
现在你自由了，
let's get some grub.
我们来吃点东西吧。
No, SpongeBob,
I'm afraid not.
不，海绵宝宝，
恐怕不是。
Well, I have a brand new bottle
of super bubbly bubble soap.
嗯，我有一瓶全新的
超级起泡的泡泡皂。
No, thanks again.
不，再次感谢。
Maybe later
we can play pirates.
也许稍后
我们可以玩海盗。
Robert, my dear, it's no use.
罗伯特，亲爱的，这没有用。
We've just grown apart.
我们刚刚分开。
What?
What do you mean?
什么？
你是什​​么意思？
I know we've had fun
in the past,
我知道我们玩得很开心
过去，
but we're just not
compatible anymore.
但我们只是不
兼容了。
It's time we went
our separate ways.
我们是时候走了
我们各走各的路。
Such is life.
这就是生活。
But Patrick,
you're my best friend.
但是帕特里克，
你是我最好的朋友。
I know it's hard,
but brace up, chap.
我知道这很难，
但振作起来，伙计。
[ sniffling]:
Yeah.
[抽鼻子]：
是的。
Maybe our paths
will cross again some day.
也许我们的路
总有一天会再次穿越。
Think fondly of me,
Mr. SquarePants.
深情地想我，
方裤先生。
Good-bye... Mr. Best Friend.
再见...最好的朋友先生。
[ sobbing]
[抽泣]
[ doorbell rings]
[门铃响]
Sandy, you there?
桑迪，你在吗？
I need some professional help.
我需要一些专业的帮助。
[ Sandy and Patrick laughing]
[桑迪和帕特里克大笑]
Patrick?
帕特里克？
Well, Pat, the new you
gets an "A" plus.
好吧，帕特，新的你
获得“A”加分。
Why, thank you, Sandra.
为什么，谢谢你，桑德拉。
I find your
intellect rather
stimulating as well.
我找到你的
而是智力
也很刺激。
SANDY:
Oh, really? Thanks.
桑迪：
哦，真的吗？谢谢。
Patrick, what do you think
about this problem?
帕特里克，你觉得怎么样
关于这个问题？
You simply change the literal
term to a coefficient
您只需更改文字即可
系数项
and the minuend will achieve
the desired quotient.
被减数将实现
所需的商。
Even the simplest of mammals
could figure it out
即使是最简单的哺乳动物
能弄清楚
with a little thought.
稍加思考。
What do you mean
by that, Patrick?
你是什么意思
帕特里克？
I'm merely suggesting
我只是建议
you lack the ability
to solve remedial equations.
你缺乏能力
求解补救方程。
Are you suggesting
I'm dumb?
你在建议吗
我傻吗？
I'd use a more sophisticated
word like "impaired."
我会使用更复杂的
像“受损”这样的词。
I think
you'd better leave.
我认为
你最好离开。
I was only
trying to help.
我只是
试图提供帮助。
I don't need your kind
of help, Mr. Know-It-All.
我不需要你这种人
求帮助，万事通先生。
I liked you better
when you were a barnaclehead!
我更喜欢你
当你还是藤壶头的时候！
[ sniffling]:
I never thought I'd lose
my best friend.
[抽鼻子]：
我从没想过我会输
我最好的朋友。
How can I compete with geniuses?
我怎样才能与天才竞争？
[ crying]
[哭泣]
Surrounded by knowledge
and no one to share it with,
被知识包围
却没有人可以分享，
no one I can call friend.
没有人我可以称之为朋友。
Who's that old chap
I used to run with?
那个老家伙是谁
我以前一起跑步？
SpongeBob.
海绵宝宝。
At least Patrick's my friend
in my memories.
至少帕特里克是我的朋友
在我的记忆中。
Ah, the glory days.
啊，辉煌岁月。
Why have we grown apart?
为什么我们渐行渐远？
I must apply all that I know
to solve this problem.
我必须应用我所知道的一切
来解决这个问题。
What could it be?
可能是什么？
What's different?
有什么不同？
[ screaming]:
What?!
[尖叫]：
什么？！
I'd do anything to have my old
buddy back by my side again.
我愿意做任何事情来拥有我的旧时光
哥们又回到我身边了。
[ banging on door]
[敲门]
SPONGEBOB [ sadly]:
Coming.
海绵宝宝[悲伤]：
来了。
Patrick--
you're kidnapping me?
帕特里克——
你在绑架我？
Yes, I am.
我是。
Yay!
耶！
What should we do?
我们应该做什么？
We are going to
have fun,
我们要去
玩得开心，
whatever
the cost may be.
无论如何
成本可能是。
Let's do this.
让我们这样做吧。
Yes, let's have some fun.
是的，让我们玩得开心吧。
Oh, yeah!
哦，是啊！
Oh, absolutely!
哦，绝对！
Are you quite sure I found
this activity to be fun?
你确定我找到了吗
这个活动好玩吗？
Yeah.
是的。
[ screaming]
[尖叫]
That was fun, huh, Patrick?
那很有趣，是吧，帕特里克？
[ mumbling]
[咕哝]
[ sighs]
[叹气]
When did the fun
go away, SpongeBob?
什么时候有好玩的
走开吧，海绵宝宝？
It went away when you
jumped off that cliff
当你的时候它就消失了
跳下那个悬崖
and knocked your head
clean off.
并敲了你的头
清理干净。
That's it.
That's what?
就是这样。
那是什么？
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
I'm going to duplicate
my actions from that day
我要复制
从那天起我的行动
to ascertain the origin
of my cha...an...nge!
以确定起源
我的改变...安...恩格！
[ distant thud]
[远处的轰鸣声]
SPONGEBOB:
Patrick!
海绵宝宝：
帕特里克！
Hold on, buddy.
坚持住，伙计。
There you go.
就这样吧。
Don't worry, Patrick.
别担心，帕特里克。
I found your head last time,
I'll find it again.
上次我找到你的头了
我会再找到它。
Not back there,
not under here.
不回到那里，
不在这里。
What if I can't find it?
如果我找不到怎么办？
Oh, poor headless Patrick.
哦，可怜的无头帕特里克。
Patrick,
your head is back.
帕特里克，
你的头回来了。
But... uh...
do you feel different?
但是……呃……
你感觉不一样吗？
Quite unchanged, actually.
事实上，完全没有变化。
I guess we'll never
have fun together again.
我想我们永远不会
再次一起玩得开心。
You said you found my dislodged
cranial cap last time.
你说你发现我被驱逐了
上次的颅盖。
Yes?
是的？
Where exactly
did you find it?
具体在哪里
你找到了吗？
Um... it was right here.
嗯……就在这里。
Hmm... impossible.
嗯……不可能。
If I landed here, the trajectory
of my dismembered skull
如果我降落在这里，轨迹
我被肢解的头骨
would cause it to come to rest
not there...
会让它停下来
不在那里...
but here,
exactly five meters due north.
但在这里，
正北五米。
But if that's your head,
then what did I pick up over...?
但如果那是你的头，
那我捡到了什么……？
Brain coral.
脑珊瑚。
No wonder you got
so smart, buddy.
难怪你得到了
太聪明了，伙计。
Here you go, Patrick,
your old head.
给你，帕特里克，
你的老头。
Are you sure you
want to give up being
smart and phosisticated
你确定你
想要放弃存在
智能且精密
to be my friend again?
再次成为我的朋友吗？
Knowledge can never
replace friendship.
知识永远不能
取代友谊。
I prefer to be an idiot.
我宁愿当个白痴。
Not just
an idiot, Patrick.
不只是
一个白痴，帕特里克。
You're also my pal.
你也是我的朋友。
Patrick?
帕特里克？
Say something, Patrick.
说点什么吧，帕特里克。
[ belching]:
Hi, SpongeBob.
[打嗝]：
嗨，海绵宝宝。
Patrick, you're back.
帕特里克，你回来了。
[ both laughing goofily]
[两人都傻笑]
[ weird jellyfish war cry]
[奇怪的水母战吼]
[ laughing goofily]
[傻笑]
[ playing jazzy tune]
[演奏爵士乐]
[ screaming]
[尖叫]
Squidward, we love you!
章鱼哥，我们爱你！
We love you Squidward,
you're my favorite.
我们爱你章鱼哥
你是我的最爱。
[ Squidward laughing]
[章鱼哥大笑]
[ alarm rings]
[警报响起]
All right, all right.
好吧，好吧。
Time for another
hideous day at work.
是时候换另一个了
工作中可怕的一天。
Uh, just hang in there,
gorgeous.
呃，坚持住，
华丽。
[ plays note on clarinet]
[用单簧管演奏音符]
Your star will shine at
the clarinet recital tomorrow.
你的星星将会闪耀
明天的单簧管演奏会。
[ chuckles]
[笑声]
Time for another glorious day
at work.
是时候迎接又一个辉煌的一天了
在工作中。
Good morning, Squidward.
早上好，章鱼哥。
And isn't it a lovely morning?
这不是一个美好的早晨吗？
Why are you playing
the clarinet?
你为什么玩
单簧管？
I'm practicing
for my clarinet recital.
我正在练习
为了我的单簧管演奏会。
Soon all of Bikini Bottom
很快所有比基尼底部
will recognize the talent
that is Squidward Tentacles.
会认可人才
那是章鱼哥的触手。
Good-bye, SpongeBoob.
再见，海绵宝宝。
See you at the Krusty Krab,
Squidward.
在蟹堡王见，
章鱼哥。
Hey Sandy-- what's this?
嘿桑迪——这是什么？
Well, this here's
my new matter transporter.
嗯，这是这里
我的新物质运输者。
It can move things
from one place to another
它可以移动东西
从一个地方到另一个地方
in the blink of an eye.
眨眼间。
Ooh, that sounds fancy.
哦，听起来很奇特。
Let me show you
how it works.
让我告诉你
它是如何运作的。
Whoa!
哇！
Where'd it go?
它去哪儿了？
Just where you think
it would be.
就在你想到的地方
会的。
[ gasps]:
Oh!
[喘气]：
哦！
Uh-oh,
I'm late for work.
呃哦，
我上班迟到了。
Think your machine could
zap me over to the Krusty Krab?
认为你的机器可以
把我带到蟹堡王那里去？
Always did want
to try a critter.
一直想要
尝试一个小动物。
Sure, why not?
当然可以，为什么不呢？
Get in there,
SpongeBob.
进去吧，
海绵宝宝。
Woo-hoo!
呜呼！
Hold on tight.
紧紧抓住。
SPONGEBOB:
Gee, Sandy, this sure feels...
海绵宝宝：
哎呀，桑迪，这确实感觉……
[ garbled]
[乱码]
Well, here we go again.
好吧，我们又来了。
Hey, Thkwidward.
嘿，特克维德。
[ laughs]
[笑]
What's going on
with this thing?
发生了什么事
用这个东西？
[ screaming]
[尖叫]
What in tarnation?
[ gasps]
什么是塔尼翁？
[喘气]
Hi, Sandy!
嗨，桑迪！
I'm not sure
what it is,
我不确定
它是什么，
but something seems
different about me.
但似乎有什么
对我来说不同。
Yeah-- me, too.
是的——我也是。
Hey, what're you doing
with my hand?
嘿，你在做什么
用我的手？
What... what am I doing
with your hand?
我……我在做什么
用你的手？
[ Squidward screams]
[章鱼哥尖叫]
What is this?
这是什么？
We're all mixed up
together.
我们都搞混了
在一起。
[ Squidward straining]
[章鱼哥紧张]
This is horrible.
这太可怕了。
I have my clarinet
recital tomorrow.
我有我的单簧管
明天的演奏会。
Oh, it's not so bad, Squidward.
噢，情况还不错，章鱼哥。
Now we can be best buddies and
do everything together forever.
现在我们可以成为最好的朋友
永远一起做所有事情。
[ Squidward screams]
[章鱼哥尖叫]
Sandy,
was this your doing?
桑迪，
这是你做的吗？
You've got to
get us separated.
你必须
让我们分开。
Well, I wish I knew how.
好吧，我希望我知道怎么做。
Well, you have to
do something.
好吧，你必须
做某事。
I can't stay
stuck to him.
我不能留下来
粘在他身上。
Hmm, I wonder what would happen
嗯，我想知道会发生什么
if I tried zapping you back
in the transporter?
如果我试着把你拉回来
在运输机中？
Uh, yeah, good idea--
let's do it.
呃，是的，好主意——
让我们开始吧。
Well, here goes nothing.
好吧，这里什么也没有。
TEACHER:
All right, children,
today is Timmy's birthday.
老师：
好吧，孩子们，
今天是蒂米的生日。
You know what that means--
ready, Timmy?
你知道这意味着什么——
准备好了吗，蒂米？
[ strange moaning]
[奇怪的呻吟声]
[ teacher and Timmy screaming]
[老师和蒂米尖叫]
Congratulations,
Mrs. Smith.
恭喜，
史密斯夫人。
You gave birth
to a healthy baby boy.
你生下了
给一个健康的男婴。
May I see my baby?
我可以看看我的宝宝吗？
Of course.
当然。
[ screams]
[尖叫声]
I've been in love
with you
我已经恋爱了
和你在一起
ever since I first
laid my eye on you.
自从我第一次
我的目光落在了你身上。
Hey, baby,
what's your name?
嘿，宝贝，
你叫什么名字？
It's no use, Sandy.
这是没有用的，桑迪。
We're still
the same.
我们还在
一样的。
Well, that's a darn shame.
嗯，这真是太遗憾了。
You know what?
你知道吗？
I was working on the blueprints
for a new invention,
我正在研究蓝图
对于一项新发明，
but it's still
in the embryonic stage.
但它仍然
处于萌芽阶段。
Try anything!
尝试任何事情！
I cannot go to my clarinet
recital like this.
我不能去我的单簧管
像这样的朗诵。
I'll continue working on it.
我会继续努力。
In the meantime,
you boys keep your heads up.
与此同时，
你们小伙子们要抬起头来。
Together forever.
永远在一起。
Misery.
苦难。
SpongeBob, hasn't anybody
taught you how to ride a bike?
海绵宝宝，没有人吗
教你如何骑自行车？
Don't worry, I'll drive.
别担心，我会开车。
Ow! Ow!
噢！噢！
SpongeBob!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
海绵宝宝！
噢！噢！噢！
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
噢！噢！噢！噢！噢！噢！噢！
I got to lay off the hot sauce.
我必须戒掉辣酱。
[ crashing]
[崩溃]
What in blazes
is going on in here?
大火中的什么
这里发生什么事了？
Oh, hi, Mr. Krabs.
哦，嗨，蟹老板。
What are you two doing
laying around?
你们两个在做什么
躺着吗？
Get to work!
开始工作吧！
If you say so.
如果你这么说的话。
Egad! What happened to you?
哎呀！你怎么了？
Uh, I don't want to know.
呃，我不想知道。
Just go do your jobs.
去做你的工作吧。
Aye, aye,
cap'n!
是啊，是啊，
船长！
Do you have to be such
an accommodating buffoon?
你一定要这样吗
一个乐于助人的小丑？
Squidward, everybody
knows I'm a sponge.
乌贼王大家
知道我是一块海绵。
I look nothing like a balloon.
我看起来一点也不像气球。
I don't have time for this.
我没有时间做这个。
I got to man
the cash register.
我得去男人
收银机。
[ straining
[ 拉紧
Whew!
哇！
Can I help you?
我可以帮你吗？
Two Krabby Patties,
please.
两块蟹肉饼，
请。
SQUIDWARD:
SpongeBob, I need two
Krabby Patties.
章鱼哥：
海绵宝宝，我需要两个
蟹肉饼。
Two Krabby Patties
coming right up.
两块蟹肉饼
马上就来了。
I can't reach the bun.
我够不到面包。
SpongeBob, what's the hold up?
海绵宝宝，怎么了？
S-sorry, Mr. Krabs,
I'm on it.
对不起，蟹老板先生，
我正在做。
Time is money, boy.
时间就是金钱，孩子。
Time is money, right.
时间就是金钱，对吧。
[ struggling]
[挣扎]
Hello, bun, at last we meet.
你好，小包子，我们终于见面了。
[ screams]
[尖叫声]
[ horrific scream]
[可怕的尖叫声]
And now for...
现在对于...
[ both screaming]
[两人都尖叫]
All right, that's it.
好吧，就是这样。
I can't afford you
jeopardizing my business.
我买不起你
危及我的生意。
You two are more trouble
than you're worth.
你们两个更麻烦
比你的价值还高。
And don't come back until you
get this problem sorted out.
直到你回来为止
解决这个问题。
SPONGEBOB:
Look on the bright side,
Squidward.
海绵宝宝：
往好的方面看，
章鱼哥。
At least we still have
each other.
至少我们还有
彼此。
That's how we got in this
predicament in the first place.
这就是我们如何进入这个
首先陷入困境。
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I'd like a moment of peace.
现在，请原谅我，
我想要片刻的平静。
[ starts playing clarinet]
[开始演奏单簧管]
Whoa!
Rock on, freaky bro.
哇！
摇滚吧，怪异兄弟。
SQUIDWARD:
Sandy! Sandy!
章鱼哥：
桑迪！沙！
Please tell me you've figured
out a way to separate us.
请告诉我你已经想到了
想办法把我们分开。
Say hello to the
molecular separator ray.
向
分子分离射线。
Hello, molecular separator ray.
你好，分子分离器射线。
Well, let's get on with it.
好吧，让我们继续吧。
My clarinet recital
is tomorrow night.
我的单簧管演奏会
是明天晚上。
Uh, well, I'm not quite
done with it yet.
呃，好吧，我还不太
还没完成呢。
What?
什么？
I'm still
putting it together.
我还在
把它放在一起。
At best
I'll have it ready,
充其量
我这就准备好
uh... day after tomorrow maybe?
呃……也许是后天？
What?
Day after tomorrow?
什么？
后天？
No, no, no, no!
不，不，不，不！
I have a performance
tomorrow.
我有表演
明天。
I can't be stuck
to that yellow freak.
我不能被困住
到那个黄色怪物。
Sandy, please--
you got to do it
before the show.
桑迪，请——
你必须这么做
演出前。
Well, uh,
I suppose...
嗯，呃，
我想...
I'll have it ready
before you go on.
我会准备好
在你继续之前。
[ straining]
[紧张]
SQUIDWARD:
Of course.
章鱼哥：
当然。
Oh, my.
哦，我的。
Where are you Sandy?
桑迪你在哪里？
Sandy?
沙？
I can't do it,
I can't go out there.
我做不到，
我不能出去那里。
Squidward...
this is your moment,
章鱼哥...
这是你的时刻，
the story you will tell
你要讲的故事
when you look back
as a... superstar.
当你回头看时
作为...超级巨星。
Superstar?
超级巨星？
Now go out there
and give them
现在出去吧
并给他们
the best darned show
they've ever seen.
最好的该死的表演
他们曾经见过。
You're right--
the show must go on.
你是对的——
演出必须继续下去。
ANNOUNCER:
Ladies and gentlefish,
播音员：
女士们和温柔的鱼，
Bikini Bottom's
community rec center
比基尼泳裤
社区休闲中心
is proud to present
Squidward Tentacles.
很自豪地呈现
章鱼哥的触手。
[ applause]
[鼓掌]
[ crowd oohs]
[人群哦]
[ playing soulful tune]
【演奏深情的曲子】
Honey, I'm scared.
亲爱的，我很害怕。
[ continues playing]
[继续播放]
[ cloth tears]
[布泪]
[ crowd gasps]
[人群喘息]
Uh... hi.
呃...嗨。
Whoa!
哇！
[ laughs]
[笑]
Rock on, freaky bro.
摇滚吧，怪异兄弟。
Yeah! Whoo!
是的！呼！
[ crowd commenting]
[群众评论]
[ cheering and whistling]
[欢呼声和口哨声]
Wow,
they really liked it.
哇，
他们真的很喜欢它。
MR. KRABS:
There you go, Squiddy.
先生。螃蟹：
就这样吧，乌贼。
[ crowd cheering]
[人群欢呼]
They... they...
they're cheering.
他们……他们……
他们在欢呼。
Superstardom-- this must
be what it feels like.
巨星——这必须
就是它的感觉。
This is what it looks like,
这就是它的样子，
what it... sounds like,
这……听起来像什么，
and... [ inhales deeply]
what it smells like.
还有……[深吸一口气]
闻起来像什么。
Wow, simply intoxicating.
哇，简直让人陶醉。
Whoo-wee!
Well, there you boys are.
哇哦！
好吧，你们孩子们就在那里。
Looks like I'm just in time.
看来我来得正是时候。
Sandy?
沙？
One blast of this
molecular separator ray
这一击一发
分子分离射线
and you'll be
separated for good.
你会
永远分开。
No, no wait--
Sandy, don't.
不，不用等——
桑迪，别这样。
[ crowd gasps]
[人群喘息]
[ disappointed grumbling]
[失望的抱怨]
[ starts playing clarinet]
[开始演奏单簧管]
I think I'm going to be sick.
我想我会生病的。
Ah, I'm out of here.
啊，我要离开这里了。
Huh?
No, wait, wait!
啊？
不，等等，等等！
Aw, come on.
噢，来吧。
Oh, my one moment
of fame gone.
哦，我的一刻
名气消失了。
There's got to be some way
to reverse this.
一定有什么办法
扭转这一局面。
No, Squidward,
that's a very sensitive device.
不，章鱼哥，
那是一个非常敏感的设备。
Squidward,
I wouldn't...
章鱼哥，
我不会...
So, what seems to be
the problem, Mr. Tentacles?
那么，似乎是什么
触手先生，有什么问题吗？
It all started when I was born.
这一切都从我出生时开始。
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org
标题为
WGBH 媒体访问小组
访问.wgbh.org
标题为
WGBH 媒体访问小组
访问.wgbh.org